# MD. AKTARUL PRAMANIK

#### Contact Address:

Rajabari, Kashem Cotton, Gazipur Sadar.

Cell : +880 1722-962343 E-mail: aktar.gub@gmail.com



### **CARREER OBJECTIVE:**

Strong desire to build up my career and develop my skill by obtaining a challenging position with a reputed organization in information technology related area. Where my academic background, experience and competency can play a significant role in achieving the organizational goals and objectives.

#### **SELF-ASSESMENTS:**

- ☐ Sincere, Self-motivated, Hardworking, and dependable
- ☐ Good interpersonal and communication skill.
- ☐ Keen understanding of job, duty, authority and responsibility.
- ☐ Having self-confident and positive approach.
- ☐ Willing to accept responsibility and to work under pressure for the best of the organization.
- ☐ Can work independent or with minimum supervision.

# AREA OF EEXPERTISE:

- ✓ Payroll Management
- ✓ Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP)
- ✓ Database Management System (Oracle)
- ✓ IT Support
- ✓ Network
- ✓ Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle Forms & Oracle Application Express (APEX)
- ✓ Basic Graphics Design (Photoshop, Illustrator & Camtasia)
- ✓ Microsoft Office & Windows OS

# **EXPERIENCE DETAILS:**

# **TOTAL YEARS OF EXPERIENCE: AROUND 15 YEARS**

1. Designation : Asst. Manager, IT

Duration : December 2022 to Continuing. : Apparel Plus Ltd. (TNZ Group) Organization

Address : Dilan Complex, Dhaka Road, Chandona Chowrasta, Gazipur Sadar

Res

| sponsibility |  |  |
|--------------|--|--|
|              | Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and |  |
|              | scanners & configuring any other IT equipment with standard software.                    |  |
|              | Ensure proper connectivity of LAN & internet and load balancing using router OS.         |  |
|              | Ensure proper connectivity, recording and maintenance of CCTV Camera & NVR.              |  |
|              | Routine maintenance, update, backup of mail server & database server.                    |  |
|              | Install configure & maintain Security system device.                                     |  |
|              | Extend LAN network using UTP/STP or Fiber optic cable.                                   |  |
|              | Routine updates the Antivirus & Routine servicing all Hardware devices of Network.       |  |
|              | Routine backup of all system devices & user data.  |  |
|              | Responding in a timely manner to end user service issues and requests;                   |  |
|              | Provide basic training to end users on their daily usage and IT security.                |  |
|              | Keep Record of purchases, warranty, issue & return record of IT equipment.               |  |
|              |  |  |

2. Designation : Asst. Manager, IT & Payroll : February 2016 to November 2022. Duration : Faiza Industries Ltd. (Florence Group) Organization Address : Bymile, Konabari, Gazipur Sadar.

# Responsibility: IT

| Configure new IT equipment with standard software.                                 |
|--|
| Maintain CCTV Camera & NVR.  |
| Maintain Security system device.   |
| Maintain proper connectivity of LAN & WAN using UTP/STP or Fiber optic cable.      |
| Routine updates the Antivirus & Routine servicing all Hardware devices of Network. |
| Provide end user support.  |

#### Responsibility: Payroll ☐ Gather input for Oracle base Payroll system. ☐ Maintain all kinds of payment from payroll system. ☐ Prepare different report copy based on COC of different buyers social & Technical audit. ☐ Implement new policy to payroll system based on buyer COC & local law. ☐ Take routine backup of attendance device & payroll system database. ☐ Prepare periodical statistical report of all payment like, Salary, OT, Annual Leave etc. ☐ Face social audit and provide all payroll related documents as per requirement. : Officer, System Administration 3. Designation : July 2009 to January 2016. Duration : UTAH Fashions Ltd. (UTAH Group) Organization **Address** : Vill: South Shalna, Post: Shalna Bazar, Gazipur Sadar, Gazipur Responsibility Download PO, Booking & Other data packet from portal to EDI system. ☐ Create Electronic Packing list and carton sticker from EDI system & delivered to finishing unit. □ Send Packing list to Commercial department for vessel booking & invoicing. Perform scan & verify or scan load process using wireless barcode scanner. ☐ Upload scan data to EDI system to proceed e-invoice □ Send Advance Ship Notice (ASN) over EDI system to forwarder & buyer. Communicate with merchants, commercial team for different issue over e-mail. ☐ Communicate with local or foreign EDI support team for software issue over e-mail & Skype. 4. Designation : System Engineer : January 2009 to June 2009 Duration : System Information Technology (SiTECH) Organization Address : 80/10, Laboratory Road, Dhaka-1205. Responsibility Assemble new PCs, Install operating system and other application software. ☐ Disk format and partition and troubleshot for old PCs. ☐ Install, configure & maintain LAN & all Hardware Support & solution of PC to Network. ☐ Provide all kind on Hardware software and network related support to our customer. 5. Designation : Asst. Officer IT Duration : August 2008 to December 2008 : M.R. Trading Corporation Organization Address : House#17, Roadd#14, Sector-13, Uttara, Dhaka-1230.Bangladesh Responsibility ☐ Solve different Hardware, software and network related problem Ensure server connectivity to smooth workflow. Maintenance all of IT resources (Hardware & Software) and ☐ Support the Data entry team. PROFESSIONAL TRAINING: 01. Payroll Management Institute : Solicitors BD Associates Duration : 11 Davs : N/A Achievement 02. Oracle Application Developer with APEX Institute : IBSC-Primax Software (Bangladesh) Ltd. Duration : 160 Hours : N/A Achievement 03. Oracle Database 11g: Program with PL/SQL Release-2 Institute : IBSC-Primax Software (Bangladesh) Ltd. Duration : 160 Hours Achievement : N/A 04. Oracle Database 12c: Introduction to SQL Institute : IBSC-Primax Software (Bangladesh) Ltd. Duration : 160 Hours

Achievement

: N/A

#### 05. Computer Aided Design

Institute : BGMEA University of Fashion & Technology (BUFT)

Duration : 6 Months
Achievement : N/A

### 06. Computer Networking, Graphics Design & Hardware

Institute : Daffodil Grameen IT Education Ltd.

Duration : 4 Months Achievement : A (Grade)

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:**

### 01. Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering

University/Board : German University of Bangladesh
Major Field of study : Computer Science and Engineering.

Passing Year : Enroll (Last semester)

Achievement : N/A

# 02. Diploma-In-Engineering (Duration: 4 Year)

Institution : Rangpur Polytechnic Institute.

Board : Bangladesh Technical Education Board, Dhaka.

Major Field of study : Computer Science and Engineering.

Passing Year : 2008

Achievement : CGPA-3.43 on Scale of 4.00 **03. Secondary School Certificate (SSC, Duration: 2 Year)**Institution : Taluk Jamira High School.

Board : Bangladesh Technical Education Board, Dhaka.

Major Field of study : General Mechanics

Passing Year : 2004

Achievement : CGPA-4.45 on Scale of 5.00

# LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY:

**Bangla:** Fluent in reading, writing, listening and speaking. (Mother tongue) **English:** Fair in reading, writing, listening and speaking. (Second Language)

# PERSONAL DETAILS:

Full Name : Md. Aktarul Pramanik
Father's Name : Late. Nurul Huda Pramanik

Mother's Name : Mrs. Ambia Begum
Date of Birth : 15 July 1987

Gender : Male

Religion : Islam (Sunni)

Nationality : Bangladeshi (by Birth)

Blood Group : B+

National ID (Smart) : 2830151714

Permanent Address : Vill: Biramervita, P.O: Monoharpur, P/S: Palashbari, Dist: Gaibandha

# **CONTACT DETAILS:**

Cell : +88 1722-962343 Email : aktar.gub@gmail.com

Contact Address : Vill: Rajabari, PO: Quashem Cotton Mill, Gazipur Sadar.

# PROFESSIONAL REFERENCE:

Azizur Rahman Managing Director Interlink Apparels Ltd. Cell: 01741-124570

E-mail: md@interlinkbd.com